Niranjani Ramalingam

Scrum Master

☑ niranjanir12@gmail.com 📞 9566414981 😲 Chennai, India 🛗 12/12/1991



Profile

Efficient Professional with a proven 8.5 years of experience in IT industry with different domains like Life Science, Telecommunication & HealthCare. Looking for a **Scrum Master role** where I can flourish my knowledge for the betterment of the individual and the organization.



Professional Experience

Scrum Master

2019 – present | Chennai, India

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd,

- Over 4 years of experience as a Scrum Master by coaching more than 5+ teams to higher levels of maturity by improving their process and ensuring they adhered to Scrum framework.
- Facilitated discussion, decision making and conflict resolution across 5 cross-functional teams.
- Monitored team backlog daily and ensured it accurately reflects the current state of the sprint.
- Identified complex impediments and assisted team in identifying the path to deliver on their sprint commitments.
- Experience in analyzing, planning, implementing and delivering sprint goals.
- Expert in conducting daily standups, sprint planning, backlog grooming, demos & retrospective meetings.
- Coached team members in Agile frameworks.
- Managed each project's scope and timeline.

Automation Test Engineer

2014 – 2019 | Chennai, India

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd,

- Over 4.5 years of experience in Functional/Manual and Automation Testing as a QA in Agile/Waterfall methodology involving HealthCare Domain.
- Experience of handling 2 teams as a QA Lead in a scrum.
- Strong Experience in Automation of Web Applications using Selenium Web driver, Maven and BDD (Cucumber).
- Experience in preparing Cucumber feature file as part of User Stories and Regression Suite and automating the feature file using Selenium.
- Involved and Experienced in Functional, System, Regression, Exploratory, GUI and UAT testing.
- Involved in Scrum ceremonies as and when required.

- Well acquainted with all the phases of SDLC and STLC.
- Used Gerrit, source code management tool for code reusage.
- Perceptive in detecting defects and proactive in execution of complex functionalities.
- As a people developer involved in planning of KT to the on boards and creating job aids as part of process improvement.
- Played pivotal role in reporting activities by providing timely updates to clients and stake holders on testing progress.
- Experienced in test management tools such as HP-QC/ALM, JIRA and Rally as a QA.



Certificates

Certified SAFe 5 Scrum Master (*Certificate ID* : 93382693-6422)

Agile Professional Certified (Certificate ID: NRAG0000037580)



Technical Skills

Agile Development & Best Practices Agile Framework

Scrum, Kanban, XP

Automation Tool: Selenium Webdriver

DataBase: MySQL Cucumber (BDD Framework)

Bug Tracking Tools: ALM/Jira Others: SOAP UI, Gerrit, GitHub,

> Eclipse IDE, MSExcel, **Powerpoint, Power BI**

Soft Skills

- Exceptional Communication & Networking Skill.
- Forecasting
- Risk Analysis
- Backlog Management
- Multitasking



Education

B.Tech Computer Science with 7.9 CGPA

2010 - 2014 | Vellore, India

Vellore Institute of Technology

12th Boards with 84%

2009 – 2010 | Vellore, India

Shrishti Matriculation Higher Secondary School

Shrishti Matriculation Higher Secondary School



Accomplishments

Awarded for excellence in Business Operation and Delivery perfection with **Avanade Orange Award for FY15 Q4**

Recognized and rewarded for excellent team delivery to client with Accenture Celebrates Excellence (ACE) award for FY17 Q2

Recognized and rewarded for excellent individual performance to client with Accenture Celebrates Excellence (ACE) award fro FY19 Q4



Canguages

English | Tamil | Hindi



Interests

Travelling | Reading Books



Declaration

I hearby declare that all the above furnished details are true to the best of my knowledge

Niranjani Ramalingam

Avadi, Chennai